以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
好了，所以我想在再次回升
okay so I'd like to pick up again on the
离子这个整齐的矩阵族
ion this neat family of matrices
循环矩阵，但首先让我说
circulant matrices but first let me say
在这里然后把它放在网上我的
here and then put it on the web my
考虑到这些项目，所以我想
thought about the projects so I think
我可以给出的最后期限是
the last deadline and I can give is the
最后一堂课所以我认为不是下一个
final class so I think that's not next
一周，但是下一周的星期三
week but Wednesday of the following week
我认为这是我们的最后一次课堂会议
I think is our last class meeting so be
很高兴他们当时或早些时候，如果
great to get them then or earlier and if
任何人或每个人都想说
anybody or everybody would like to tell
关于他们的课程
the class a little bit about their
项目，你知道这是一个友好的
project you know it's a friendly
观众和我很高兴
audience and and I'd be happy to make
空间和时间，所以给我一个
space and time for that so so send me an
如果你或者给我发电子邮件
email if you or and and give me the
如果你愿意，可以提前预定
project earlier if you would like to
只是在课堂上说几句话，甚至是
just say a few words in class or even if
你愿意多说几句话
you are willing to say a few words in
我会说是的，因为我意识到了
class I'll say yeah because I realize
是的，所以其他问题也是如此
yeah okay so other questions about so so
我们完成了所有的p-sets等等
we're finished with all p-sets and so on
所以这真的只是一个项目，是的
so it's really just a project and yeah
它是如何分级好的问题，但它是
how is it graded good question but it's
会成为我
going to be me
我想是的，所以我会阅读所有的项目
I guess so so I'll read all the projects
不知怎的，你拿出一个等级
and come up with a grade somehow you
知道我，我希望你们有
know I my I hope you guys have
了解我，你知道我的感觉
understood that I'm you know my feeling
是这门课程的成绩是
is that the grades in this course are
会因为偏高而偏高
going to be on the high side because
他们应该是啊我认为这是它的
they should be yeah I think it's a it's
那种课程，我问你
that kind of a course and I'm asked you
无论如何要做相当数量
for to do a fair amount and anyway
这是我的起点，而且还有一个
that's my starting basis and there's a
很多主题，如循环矩阵
lot of topics like circulant matrices
我不是要能够给
that I'm not going to be able to give
你当然是我的一部分
you a piece set about but I of course
这些都是可以密切
these are closely can
这对于离散傅立叶变换
that to the discrete Fourier transform
所以让我写下这个名字吧
so let me just write the name of the
伟大的人傅立叶如此离散
great man Fourier so the discrete
傅立叶变换就像你所知道的那样
Fourier transform is as you know very
非常重要的算法
very important algorithm in in
工程学和数学
engineering and in mathematics
到处都是傅立叶只是一个关键的想法
everywhere Fourier is just a key idea
所以我觉得这是一个好的知道
and so I think it's just good to know
关于那些循环矩阵是什么
about those so circulant matrices are
与有限大小连接
connected with with the finite size
矩阵矩阵和一些矩阵
matrices matrices of size and some are
循环矩阵将由n和n组成
circulant matrices will be n by n and
你还记得这个特殊形式
you remember this special form so this
这是关于这些矩阵的关键点
is a key point about these matrices see
它们的定义不是n平方
that they are defined by not n squared
如果你告诉我的话，只有n个条目
entries only n if you tell me just the
矩阵的第一行，这就是全部
first row of the matrix and that's all
你会告诉MATLAB说C0C1C2C.
you would tell MATLAB say C 0 C 1 C 2 C
和负1并且为循环
and minus 1 and for a circulant that's
所有我需要知道的因为这些
all I need to know because these
这条对角线的对角线是恒定的
diagonals are constant this diagonal is
常数C1然后完成
constant C 1 and then gets completed
这里C两个对角线来到C2然后
here C two diagonal come to C 2 and then
在这里循环完成所以M
gets completed cyclically here so M
数字，而不是n平方和那个
numbers and not n squared and that the
我提到的原因或原因是
reason I mention that or a reason is
那是一个很大的卖点
that's there that's a big selling point
当你去同一台机器的应用程序
when you go to applications same machine
学习图像让你记住
learning in for images so you remember
机器学习的大局
the big picture of machine learning
深刻的学习是你的
deep deep learning was that you had
样本
samples
很多样本让我们说n个样本
a lot of samples let's say n samples
也许然后这个图像中的每个样本
maybe and then each sample in this image
部分将是一个图像所以事情是
part will be an image so the thing is
图像由其像素描述
that an image is described by its pixels
如果我有千千万
and if I have a thousand by thousand
像素这样一百万
pixel so that's a million a million
像素它是特征向量的
pixels it the the feature vector the
与一个样本相关联的向量
vector that's associated with one sample
是巨大的是如此巨大，所以我发泄
is enormous is enormous so so so I vents
安瓿但也许可能很好，如果他们是
ampuls but maybe maybe well if they're
百万突然变成的颜色
in color that million suddenly becomes
三百万说三百万
three million so say three million
功能所以我们的矢量我们的矢量
features so our vectors our vector of
那整个计算深刻
that the whole computation of deep
学习与我们的向量一起工作
learning works with our vectors with
三百万个组件，这意味着
three million components and that means
如果我们不这样做的话
that in the ordinary way if we didn't do
我们将成倍增加的任何特殊事物
anything special we would be multiplying
那些大小像三的矩阵
those by matrices of size like three
百万三百万我们会
million times three million we would be
计算的是这是许多像权重
computing that many weights that's like
这是不可能的，我们会这样
impossible that's like and we would be
为...中的每一层计算
computing that for for each layer in the
深度网络，所以它会上升到一个正常的
deep network so it would go up a normai
它增加了三百万
it go up so three million by three
百万只是我们无法计算我们
million is just we can't compute we
不能使用梯度下降来优化
can't use gradient descent to optimize
许多重量所以重点是这一点
that many weight so the point is that
深度学习中的矩阵是
the matrices in deep learning are
特别的，他们不依赖他们
special and they don't depend they they
就像他们可能的循环矩阵一样
are like circulant matrices they might
不循环所以循环矩阵
not loop around so circulant matrices
有这样的循环功能，使
have this cyclic feature that that makes
理论完美非常好
the theory perfect extremely nice
但一般我们当然
but of course in general we have
矩阵让我们说Tt0不变
matrices let's say T t0 constant
对角线，也许是一堆对角线
diagonals and maybe bunch of diagonals
在这里不一定是对称的或
in here not necessarily symmetric or
它们可能是对称的，但它们不是
they might be symmetric but they're not
循环所以这些矩阵叫什么
cyclic so what are these matrices called
好吧，他们有一堆名字，因为
well they have a bunch of names because
他们是如此重要，他们是他们
they're so important they're they're
线性移位不变或线性时间
linear shift invariant or linear time
无论什么是正确的词
invariant whatever is the right word in
你的背景所以他们就是这样
your context so so they're they're
卷积你可以称之为
convolutions you could call it a
卷积矩阵乘以时
convolution matrix when they multiply by
其中一个矩阵，我想我要走了
one of these matrices I guess I'm going
称它为T优正在尽
to call it t you're doing our
卷积，我会写得更好
convolution and I'll better write down
我们卷积的公式你是
the formula for our convolution you're
除非是，否则不进行循环卷积
not doing a cyclic convolution unless
矩阵周期循环这个时候
the matrix cycles round this would when
你乘以C这会给你一个
you multiply by C this would give you a
循环卷积说我是否乘以C
cyclic convolution say if I multiply C
通过一些向量V，结果是
by some vector V the result is the
C矢量的循环卷积
cyclic convolution of the C vector with
V矢量这么大C是一个矩阵但是
the V vector so big C is a matrix but
但它完全由第一个定义
but it's completely defined by its first
行或第一列，所以它真的是我
row or first column so it's really I
只是在那里有一个矢量操作
just have a vector operation there and
这是一个循环的，在这里T次
it's a cyclic one and over here T times
向量V将是的卷积
a vector V will be the convolution of a
T矢量与V但不循环和
T vector with V but not cyclic and
可能这些就是那些
probably these are the ones that would
实际上是进来机器学习的
actually come in to machine learning so
线性移位不变线性时间
linear shift invariant linear time
不变
invariant
我把它叫做这么掩盖人们会
I would call it so mask people would
称之为三元组矩阵，这就是它
call it a triplets matrix so that's
这就是我用字母T的原因
that's why I used the letter T in
工程它将是一个过滤器或
engineering it would be a filter or a
卷积或是恒定的对角线
convolution or are constant diagonal
矩阵这些出现在各种各样的地方
matrix these come up all sorts of places
他们进入机器学习
and they come up in in machine learning
和图像处理，但基本上
and with image processing but basically
因为你在某一点上做了什么
because what you're doing at one point
在图像中它几乎就是你的样子
in an image it's pretty much what you're
要在其他点做
going to do at the other points
你不会想出特别的
you're not gonna figure out special
每个小像素的权重
weights for each little pixel in the
像你要去如果你必须要
image you're going to take if you have
一张图片说你有一张图片
an image say you have an image with with
数以万亿计的像素
zillions of pixels
好吧，你可能想减少我的意思
well you might want to cut down I mean
你最明智的做法是非常明智的
you'd be very sensible to do some max
汇集一些池化操作
pooling some pooling operations to make
它小，所以真的很喜欢我们没关系
it smaller so that's really like okay we
我们不能不想要这个更大的系统
can't we don't want this larger system
让我们减少它，以便最大限度地利用它
let's just reduce it so max pooling that
操作会说他们三个
operation would be say take them three
在九个像素的时间和替换
at a time from nine pixels and replace
那九个像素乘以一个像素所以最大
that nine pixels by one pixel so the max
这九个数字中的一个
of those nine numbers that would be a
非常简单的操作，只是减少
very simple operation that just reduces
使尺寸变小的尺寸
the dimension that's make it smaller
减少尺寸
reduce the dimension
好吧，这是一个廉价的方式来做到这一点
okay so that's a cheap way to make it
制作四次或九次图像
make an image for four times or nine
时间或者小64倍但是
times or 64 times smaller but the
卷积部分现在不是
convolution part now so that's not
涉及卷积，这是一个不同的
involving convolution that's a different
如果我采取这里的操作甚至不是线性的
operation here not even linear if I take
每个框中的最大值不是线性的
the max in each box that's not a linear
操作，但这是一个快速的，所以
operation so but it's a fast one okay so
现在哪里循环飙升卷积
now where do circulant soar convolution
或三元组矩阵或过滤器来
or triplets matrices or filters come
进入它所以我会忘记最大值
into it so I'll forget about the max
冷却假设发生了，我
cooling suppose that's happened and I
N还有一个非常大的系统
still have a very big system with N
平方
squared
每个像素和平方特征
pixels and squared features in for each
样本，所以我想操作
sample so that's so I want to operate on
通过矩阵像往常一样我想
that by matrices as usual I want to
选择权重来突出
choose the weights to bring out the
重点，所以整个想法都在
important points so the whole idea is on
这样的图像我将使用卷积
a image like that I'll use a convolution
我将使用相同的操作
I'll use this the same operation is
发生在每一点，所以如果忘记了
happening at each point so if so forget
如果我能找到，最大部分让我擦除
the max part let me erase if I can find
橡皮擦在这里好吧所以我不会
an eraser here okay so I'm I'm not gonna
我们已经完成了这个，所以我现在就完成了
we've done this so that's done now I
想重量乘以它使
want to multiply it by weight so that
那已经做好了所以我是什么
that's already done okay so what am I
期待做什么是什么样的
looking to do what was it what kind of a
过滤器会做一个低通滤波器
job would a filter do a low-pass filter
会杀死或几乎杀死高
would kill or nearly kill the high
如果我愿意的话，可以对噪音进行调频
frequencies the noise so if I wanted to
在那里我会使用一个更简单的图像
get a simpler image there I would use a
洛佩
lope
过滤器可能就是这个
filter which might just it might be this
这个过滤器让我放入
this filter here with let me just put in
一些可以说是a的数字
some numbers that would that would say a
一半，所以我平均每个
half and a half so I'm averaging each
像素与邻居只是取出
pixel with its neighbor just to take out
一些高频率低
some of the high frequencies the low
频率是恒定的图像黑色
frequencies are constant image a black
所有的黑色图像都不会出现
all black image would come out not
改变了但是一个非常高度斑点的图像
changed but a very highly speckled image
将被大大消除
would get largely removed by that
平均，所以我的想法是一样的
averaging so I it's the same idea that
所有人说没有处理
comes up in all of say no processing
过滤所以只是为了完成这个
filtering so just to complete this
想到为什么更广泛的神经
thought of how why does a wider neural
网，所以我回答这个问题为什么
nets so I'm answering this question why
他们是如何进入机器学习的
how do they come in machine learning
所以他们来样的时候
so they come when when the samples are
图像，然后很自然地用AA
images and then it's natural to use a a
恒定对角矩阵一个移位
constant diagonal matrix a shift
不变矩阵而不是任意的
invariant matrix and not an arbitrary
矩阵，所以我们只需要计算
matrix so we're we only have to compute
n权重，而不是N平方是啊
n weights and not N squared yeah
这就是重点，这是一个原因
so that's the point so that's one reason
谈论卷积和
for talking about convolution and
本课程中的循环矩阵I.
circulant matrices in this course I
猜我觉得另一个原因是
guess I feel another reason is that
与DFT有关的一切
everything to do with the DFT with
傅立叶和傅立叶的傅立叶
Fourier it with Fourier and Fourier
变换和隐斜矩阵
transforms and phoria matrices
这就像你必须了解我的东西
that's just like stuff you got to know I
这意味着你每次拥有自己
mean that's every time you have a you're
处理矢量
dealing with vector
这是我们正在转移的一种转变
that are sort of shift we're shifting
向量进入它是为了
the vectors comes into it that's for
EA会进来，所以这只是我们
EA's gonna come in so it's just we
应该看到你好，所以现在我可以
should see for you okay so now can i
我会回到这个特别好的案例
I'll go back to this specially nice case
矩阵循环的位置
where the where the the matrix loops
我周围有这种循环
around where I have this cyclic
卷积所以这是-循环的
convolution so so this are-- cyclic
因为周围的东西和循环
because of the looping around stuff and
让我们找到哦，那是什么意思
let's find oh so what was the point of
上次我开始这个
last time I I started with this
置换矩阵和置换
permutation matrix and the permutation
矩阵有C0等于0C1等于1和
matrix has C 0 equals 0 C 1 equal 1 and
C的其余部分都是0所以它只是
the rest of the C's are 0 so it's just
乘法的这个效果得到
the effect of multiplying by this get a
在这附近的盒子效果
box around it here the effect of
乘以这个排列矩阵
multiplying by this permutation matrix
是转移一切，然后带来
is to shift everything and then bring
最后一个到顶部所以这是一个
the last one up to the top so it's a
循环移位所以治安官是六件事
cyclic shift so six things sheriff is
外面，我想在最后
outside and I guess at the very end of
上次我问它的时候
last time I was asking about its
特征值和特征向量也可以
eigenvalues and eigenvectors so can we
来到那个问题所以这是一个
come to that question so that's a
我在这里开始提出一切问题
starting question for everything here I
我猜我们也明白这一点
guess we've understood that too to get
更深入到矩阵的特征值
deeper into a matrix its eigenvalues
特征向量或奇异值奇异
eigenvectors or singular value singular
矢量实际上是什么方式
vectors are the way to go actually what
将是那个的奇异价值
would be the singular values of that
矩阵，所以，呃，是的，让我们来吧
matrix so that's uh yeah just lets let's
只考虑奇异的价值观
just think about singular values and
那么我们就会明白为什么它的特征值
then we'll see why why its eigenvalues
我们
we
说-他们是独一无二的
saying - they're one of the singular
它们的排列矩阵的值
values of a permutation matrix they're
所有这一个矩阵都是一个
all one all one that matrix is a
正交矩阵所以SVD的
orthogonal matrix so the the SVD of the
矩阵就像排列和
matrix just has like the permutation and
那么身份因此是西格玛
then the identity is therefore the Sigma
因此西格玛是我的伙伴
so Sigma is I for this mate for this
矩阵不是那么奇异值不
matrix not so the singular values don't
现在我想如果我们那是因为P
and now I guess if we that's because P
转置P是单位矩阵
transpose P is the identity matrix
任何时候我都认为那是正交的
anytime I have that that's an orthogonal
矩阵然后可能随时P转置P
matrix then maybe anytime P transpose P
是奇异值的标识
is the identity the singular values will
是身份和特征的本征值
be the eigen values of the identity and
就在那里，他们只是那些人
that's there they're all just ones the
P的本征值是我们想要的
eigen values of P that's what we want to
发现所以，让我们这样做
find so let's do that
P的特征值是好的，所以一种方法是
okay eigen values of P so one way is to
采取P减去lambda我就是我们的方式
take P minus lambda I that's the way we
教在1806年，从来没有如此反复使用
teach in 1806 and never use again so
它是对角线上的负λ和
it's minus lambda on the diagonal and of
当然P坐在这里然后
course P is sitting up here and then
好吧，所以现在遵循1806规则我
okay so now following the 1806 rule I
应该采取那个确定的权利和
should take that determinate right and
将它设置为零为什么不是这一个
set it to zero why don't one this is one
在极少数情况下我们可以
of the very few occasions we can
真正做到这一点，以便让我做，所以
actually do it so allow me to do it so
这个井的决定因素是什么？
what is the determinant of this well
是的，那就是那个lambda
yeah there's that there's that lambda to
第四个，我想我认为这是羔羊
the fourth and I guess I think it's lamb
到第四个减去一个，我认为是
to the fourth minus one I think that's
正确的决定因素
the right determinant
那肯定有财产所以我
that certainly has has property so I
将设置为零，那么我会找到
would set that to zero then I would find
那个特征值会
that the the eigenvalues for that will
是一减一，我和减去我
be one and minus one and I and minus I
而他们是为如果他们的
and they're the for for if they're the
一个lambda的第四根是第四个
fourth roots of one lambda the fourth
等于我们这是我们的等式
equal one that's our that's our equation
这是我们的特征值方程lambda
that's our eigenvalue equation lambda
第四个等于1或lambda到N.
the fourth equal 1 or lambda to the N
续集之一，所以会是什么
sequel one so what would be the
自由p8x8的特征值
eigenvalues for for the free p 8x8 this
当然是复杂的平面
is the complex plane of course real and
想象中有一个Tigan值
imaginary so that's got a Tigan values
我们想成为的8次方将是
we want to be the 8th power would be the
身份和那意味着lambda到
identity and that means that lambda to
的8次方是一个特征值
the 8th power is one for the eigenvalues
什么是八个解决方案
and what are the eight solutions every
八度多项式方程
polynomial equation of degree eight has
得到八个解决方案
got to have eight solutions
那是高斯的基本定理
that's Gauss's fundamental theorem of
代数八种解决方案那么它们是什么
algebra eight solutions so what are they
那八个数字是八分之一
what are the eight numbers whose eighth
权力给你们所有人都知道的
power gives one you all probably know
他们所以他们当然是第八个
them so they're one of course the eighth
一个的力量是-1的能量，即第八个
power of one is power of -1 the 8th
减去我的权力和其他人都
power of minus I and the other guys are
就在这里，一个人的根源是平等的
just here the roots of one are equally
围绕圆圈间隔，所以傅立叶是
spaced around the circle so Fourier is
进来吧
come in
你知道傅立叶在他们看到的时候会醒来
you know Fourier wakes up when they sees
这张照片就在这里
that picture for here is gonna be here
它将在特征向量中
and it'll be in the eigenvectors so
你还可以使用特征值
you okay with the eigenvalues the
P的特征值将是这多少让
eigenvalues of p will be this number so
我们最好给这个号码命名
we better give a name to this number
让我们看看我打电话给那个号码W.
let's see I'm gonna call that number W
这将是我超过8的2pi
and it'll be e to the 2 pi I over 8
因为角度是2pi
right because the angle is 2 pi the
整个角度是2pi，除以8
whole angle is 2 pi divided it by in 8
所以那是2pi超过82pi
pieces so the that's 2 pi over 8 2 pi
以及四个矩阵结束
over and for a matrix of four the end by
结束排列是的，所以这个数字是W.
end permutation yeah so that's number W
当然这个家伙是平方的
and of course this guy is is w squared
这个是WQw4wv67和w8
this one is WQ w 4 w v 6 7 and w 8 is
相同1右所以右以及那些
the same as 1 right so right well those
我把那些数字放在那里的原因
the reason I put those numbers up there
是他们进入特征向量
is that they come into the eigenvectors
以及特征值
as well as the eigenvalues
它们是这八个特征值
they are the eigenvalues these eight
数字12345678是八
numbers 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 are the eight
矩阵的特征值
eigenvalues of the matrix
这是一个44乘4的情况
it's a here's the 4 4 by 4 case the
矩阵是一个正交矩阵哦什么的
matrix is an orthogonal matrix Oh what
这会告诉我们有关特征向量的信息
does that tell us about the eigenvectors
正交矩阵的特征向量
the eigenvectors of an orthogonal matrix
是正交的
are orthogonal
就像对称矩阵一样，你也是
just like symmetric matrices so do you
知道那个小矩阵列表
know that little list of matrices with
正交特征向量如此好，我要去了
orthogonal eigenvectors so ok I'm going
称他们为Q所以QI点缀着QJ
to call them Q so Q I dotted with Q J
内在的产品是
the inner product is
如果我不是J，如果我会说0，则为1或01
1 or 0 1 if I would say 0 if I is not J
正交特征向量现在是什么
orthogonal eigenvectors now what
矩阵具有正交特征向量
matrices have orthogonal eigenvectors
我们要回到线性代数
we're going back to linear algebra
因为这是这就像一个
because this is this is like a
知道这个家庭的基本事实
fundamental fact to know this family of
奇妙的矩阵矩阵
wonderful matrices matrices with
正交特征向量所以告诉我一个
orthogonal eigenvectors so tell me one
你知道的一堆矩阵
bunch of matrices that you know has
正交特征向量对称和
orthogonal eigenvectors symmetric and
特征值有什么特别之处
what is special about the eigenvalues
他们是真实的，但还有其他的
they're real but there are other
具有正交的矩阵
matrices that have orthogonal
特征向量，我们真的应该知道
eigenvectors and we really should know
关于那些家伙整个故事
the whole story about those guys that
他们太重要了，不知道
they're too important not to know so
什么是另一个饥荒-一堆
what's another famine other-- bunch of
矩阵所以这些对称矩阵
matrices so these symmetric matrices
有正交特征向量和真实
have orthogonal eigenvectors and real
对称的，则特征值将是
symmetric then the eigenvalues will be
真正的其他家庭是什么其他
real well what other family what other
矩阵的种类是正交的
kind of matrices have orthogonal
特征向量但它们可能很复杂
eigenvectors but they might be complex
和特征值可能是复杂，所以
and the eigenvalues might be complex so
而你只需要你可以不知道
and you just have to you can't know
傅立叶没说，我可以处理
Fourier without saying ok I can deal
这个复杂的数字确定
with this complex number ok
什么是另一个矩阵族
so what's another family of matrices
具有正交特征向量的是
that has orthogonal eigenvectors yes
对角线肯定是正确的，然后我们知道
diagonal for sure right and then we know
我们有特征向量
that we we have the eigenvectors are go
到单位矩阵权呀等等
into the identity matrix right yeah so
我们知道对角线的一切
we know everything about diagonal ones
你可以说那些都包括在内
you could say those are included in
对称现在让我们得到一些新的
symmetric now let's get some new ones
还有什么
what else
正交矩阵计数
orthogonal matrices count
正交矩阵，如排列或
orthogonal matrices like permutations or
像旋转或像反射一样
like rotations or like reflections
正交矩阵和什么是特殊的
orthogonal matrices and what's special
关于它们的特征值的特征值
about their eigenvalues the eigenvalues
正交矩阵的大小是
of an orthogonal matrix the magnitude is
1确实必须有一个，因为一个
1 exactly there has to be one because an
正交矩阵不会改变
orthogonal matrix doesn't change the
向量q的长度x乘以
length of the vector q times x has the
所有向量和x的长度与x4相同
same length as x 4 for all vectors and
特别是对于特征向量，如果
in particular for eigenvectors so if
这是一个特征向量qx等于
this was an eigenvector q x would equal
lambdaX，现在如果等于那个
the lambda X and now if that equals that
那么lambda必须是1的大小
then lambda has to be 1 the magnitude of
lambda必须是1当然很复杂
lambda has to be 1 of course complex
预计这里会有数字
numbers are expected here and that's
正是我们在这里看到的一切
exactly what we're seeing here all the
排列的特征值非常大
eigenvalues of permutations are very
特殊的正​​交矩阵II不会
special orthogonal matrices I I won't
将排列分别添加到列表中
add permutations separately to the list
但他们现在算是这样的了
but they count now what so this has the
事实上，这是在名单上告诉我们的
fact that this is on the list tells us
我们要去的特征向量
that the eigenvectors that we're going
找到正交我们没有
to find are orthogonal we don't have to
做一个单独的检查，看看他们是谁
do a separate check to see that they are
一旦我们计算出它们就必须存在
once we compute them they have to be
还有的特征向量我们
there are the eigenvectors of our
正交矩阵现在我可以问你
orthogonal matrix now I could ask you
让我们保持这个打算得到整个
let's keep going with this get the whole
列出这里以及对称的那些
list here along with symmetric there's
另一堆人反对称大
another bunch of guys anti-symmetric big
对付，但这些都是重要的，所以
deal but those are important so
对称意味着转置等于a
symmetric means a transpose equals a
对角线你知道转置等于a
diagonal you know a transpose equals a
反正交矩阵现在我
inverse orthogonal matrices now I'm
打算放入反对称矩阵
going to put in anti-symmetric matrices
哪里
where
转置是减去你的想法
a transpose is minus a what do you think
你知道的特征值
you know about the eigenvalues for
反对称矩阵
anti-symmetric matrices
我们举一个反对称的例子
shall we take an example anti-symmetric
矩阵说零一个零和负一
matrix say zero zero one and minus one
什么是好，如果那特征值
what are the eigenvalues of that well if
我减去拉姆达从从
I subtract lambda from the from the
对角线并采取确定的我得到
diagonal and takes a determinate I get
lambda平方加1右等于0所以
lambda squared plus 1 right equals 0 so
lambda是我或者我是旋转
lambda is I or minus I that's a rotation
矩阵本身是啊
matrix itself yeah
是的，它是一个90度的旋转
yeah it's a it's a rotation through 90
度，所以不可能是真实的
degrees so there could not be a real
特征值你有没有想过这个
eigenvalue have you thought about that
或者如果我每次都旋转一个真正的特征向量
or a real eigenvector if i rotate every
矢量怎么可能出来一个矢量
vector how could a vector come out a
我自己怎么样才能拥有一个
multiple of itself how could I have a
转置时间等于lambda的向量
transpose times a vector equal lambda
我已经旋转它的矢量时代了
times a vector I've rotated it and yet
不知何故，它在同一个方向
it's in the same direction well somehow
这可能是想象中的
that's possible in imaginary in in
虚构的空间，并非不可能
imaginary space and not not possible in
真实的空间好吧所以这里是一个lambdas
real space okay so so here's a lambdas
是虚构的，现在终于告诉我了
are imaginary and now finally tell me
如果你知道整个的名字，你
you if you know the name of the whole
包括所有矩阵的矩阵族
family of matrices that includes all of
那些和更多的矩阵
those and more of matrices with
正交向量所以那是什么
orthogonal eigenvectors so what is that
那么什么是特殊属性
what are the special properties then
这些将是矩阵，所以我称之为M
these would be matrices so I call them M
对于矩阵，所以它是一个正交的
for matrix so it's a has orthogonal
你是矢量所以它是Q倍
you're vector so it's a Q times the
对角线时间q转置得很好
diagonal times q transpose that's well
我真的写下来了
I've really written down somehow I
没有为他们写下名字但是
haven't written a name down for them but
这就是他们获得他们的方式我是
that's the way they way to get them I'm
允许任何正交的特征向量
allowing any orthogonal eigenvectors
对不起，这是对角线我对角线
sorry this is diagonal I've diagonalized
矩阵，在这里，我得到任何
the the matrix and here the I get any
特征值所以我想要最后一个人
eigenvalue so I want to the final guy on
此列表允许任何特征值
this list allows any eigenvalues any
复杂的数字，但我可以矢量
complex numbers but there I can vectors
我想要正交
I'm want to be orthogonal
所以这就是为什么我将q怎么这么会
so that's why I have the Q so how would
你认识到这样一个矩阵，是什么
you recognize such a matrix and what is
他们的名字，这样是那么这
the name for them so that is so this
我们可能会超过1806年
we're going beyond 1806 because probably
我没有提到这个名字的名字
I don't mention that name the name for
这些矩阵在1806年，但我可以和
these matrices in 1806 but I could and
任何人都知道这种形式的矩阵是
anybody know it a matrix of that form is
正常矩阵法线就是这样
a normal matrix normal so that's the
总列表是正常名称
total list is a normal name
所以正常的矩阵看起来就像我有的那样
so normal matrices look like that I have
为那些想到这一点的人道歉
to apologize for whoever thought up that
名字正常我的意思是那样的好
name normal I mean like that's like okay
在多一点思考，你可能已经
in a little more thought you could've
想出更有意义的事情
come up with something more meaningful
不仅仅是说正常哦上帝说矩阵
than just say normal oh god says matrix
这与正常情况完全相反
that's the absolute opposite of normal
几乎所有的矩阵都不正常
almost all matrices are not normal
所以无论如何，这就是他们所谓的
so anyway but that's what they're called
正常的矩阵，最后你怎么样
normal matrices and finally how do you
认识每个人的正常矩阵
recognize a normal matrix everybody
知道如何识别对称
knows how to recognize a symmetric
矩阵或对角矩阵，我们甚至
matrix or a diagonal matrix and we even
知道如何识别正交
know how to recognize an orthogonal
矩阵或歪斜或反对称但如何
matrix or skew or anti-symmetric but how
你有什么简单的测试方法一
do you what's the quick test for a
普通矩阵我会告诉你
normal matrix well I'll just tell you
普通矩阵有m个转置m
that a normal matrix has m transpose m
等于mm转置我在这里说
equal m m transpose I'm talking here
关于真正的矩阵，我真的应该
about real matrices and I really should
转向复杂，但让我想到
move to complex but let me just think of
它们是真实的，所以如果麻烦的话
them as real so if well the trouble is
他们的矩阵可能是真实的，但是
they the matrices might be real but the
特征向量不会是真实的
eigenvectors are not going to be real
并且特征值不会
and the eigenvalues are not going to be
真正所以我真的很抱歉说真的
real so really I I'm sorry to say really
再次，我应该走出走出的
again I should get out of the out of the
真实的限制，我怎么得到
limitation to real yeah and how do I get
出于对我真实的限制
out of the limitation to real what do I
如果M是复数矩阵，则在此处改变
change here if M is a complex matrix
而不是一个真正的矩阵然后
instead of a real matrix then whenever
你转置它你应该采取它
you transpose it you should take its
复杂的共轭所以现在就是这样的
complex conjugate so now that that's the
真实的东西，这是正常的事情
real thing that's the normal thing
这是正确的事情呀右右
that's the right thing yeah right right
事情更好，所以这是正常的
things better okay so that's a normal
矩阵和你可以检查，如果你
matrix and and you can check that if you
拿了那个米，你想出了m
took that m and you figured out m
转置并做到它会起作用
transpose and did that it would work
因为最后队列取消了
because in the end the queues cancel and
你只有两个对角矩阵
you're just have two diagonal matrices
那就是那种自动的
there and that's sort of automatic that
对角矩阵通勤这么正常
diagonal matrices commute so a normal
矩阵是与其交换的矩阵
matrix is one that commutes with its
用它的转置或转置通勤
transpose commutes with its transpose or
它的共轭转置在复合体中
its conjugate transpose in the complex
案件确定为什么我这么简单地说
case ok why did I say all that simply
因为哦，我猜是这样的
because oh I guess that so the
置换P是正交的，所以
permutation P is is orthogonal so so
它的特征向量，我们要去
it's eigen vectors which we're going to
写下一分钟是正交的
write down in a minute are orthogonal
但实际上这个矩阵C将是一个
but actually this matrix C will be a
正常矩阵我没有看到即将到来
normal matrix I didn't see that coming
当我开始谈论这些家伙时
as I started talking about these guys
是的，如果我这是一个正常的矩阵
yeah so that's a normal matrix if I
因为因为循环矩阵
because because circulant matrices
通勤任何两个循环矩阵
commute any two circulant matrices
通勤C1C2等于C2C1现在
commute C 1 C 2 equals C 2 C 1 and now
如果C2是转置，那么这里是a
if C 2 is the transpose of so here's a
矩阵是啊所以这些都是矩阵
matrix yeah so these are matrices here
循环萨尔通勤它有点
circulant Sall commute it's a little
当你繁殖时，矩阵族
family of matrices when you multiply
他们聚一聚更多的人
them together you get more of them
你只是呆在那个小小的地方
you're just staying in that little
具有n个参数的循环世界
circulant world with n parameters and
一旦你知道你知道的第一行
once you know the first row you know all
其他行，所以实际上他们都是
the other rows and so in fact they all
拥有相同的特征向量所以现在让我
have the same eigen vector so now let me
可以肯定我们得到了特征向量
that may be sure we get the eigenvectors
直接没关系
straight okay
好吧，我可以在P的载体也将是
okay I can vectors of of P will also be
我能用C的向量是因为它是一个
I can vectors of C is because it's a
P的力量组合，所以我
combination of powers of P so once I
找我发现P的特征向量
find the eigenvectors of P I've found
任何循环矩阵的特征向量
the eigenvectors of any circulant matrix
这些特征向量非常特殊
and these eigenvectors are very special
那是与傅立叶的联系
and that's the connection to fourier
这就是我们期望连接的原因
that's why we expect a connection to
傅立叶因为我们有东西
fourier because we have something
这是免费的
periodic and that's what free is
完全是好的，所以这些是什么
entirely about okay so what are these
特征向量
eigenvectors
让我们把p变成四乘四，好吧
let's take p to be four by four okay so
特征向量是我们记得的
the eigenvectors are so we remember the
特征值是lambda等于1lambda
eigenvalues are lambda equal 1 lambda
等于-1lambda等于I和lambda
equal minus 1 lambda equal I and lambda
等于减去我有四个特征向量
equal minus I got four eigenvectors to
找到，当我们找到你将拥有的那些
find and when we find those you'll have
一张图片好的是什么是特征值
a picture ok what's the eigenvalue
本征向量为等于拉姆达11111
eigenvector for a lambda equal 1 1 1 1 1
所以让我把它变成一个矢量和
so let me make it into a vector and the
lambda等于-1的特征向量是
eigenvector for lambda equal minus 1 is
所以我希望这种转变能够改变
so I want this shift to change every
如果我更好地交替那些，那么签字
sign so if I I better alternate those
标志，如果我转移它，一个人去
signs so that if I shift it the one goes
到-1-1到1那么本征
to the -1 -1 goes to the 1 so the eigen
价值是负1现在怎么样
value is minus 1 now what about the
特征值
eigenvalues of
我们很遗憾特征向量
we're sorry the eigenvector that goes
特征值我所以我想要我想要的
with eigenvalue i so i'm looking i want
如果我用一个开始它，我做的
if i start it with one and i do the
排列我认为我只想要我
permutation i think i just want i I
平方我在那里立刻，我想
squared I cubed there and I think with
这个减去II的人认为我想要的
this guy with minus I I think I want the
矢量1减去我减去我平方减去我
vector 1 minus I minus I squared minus I
立刻，所以没有停下来检查让我们
cubed so without stopping to check let's
只看到这里的好点
just see the the nice point here all the
特征向量的所有组件
all the components of eigenvectors are
在这张照片中我们都在这里
on in this picture all the here we've
得到八个特征向量一个Tigan值a
got eight eigenvectors a Tigan values a
特征向量具有的数字向量
digan vectors the eigenvectors have
8个组件和每个组件是
eight components and every component is
权力就是这八个数字中的一个
a power is one of these eight numbers
整个事情是由...构建的
the whole thing is constructed from the
相同的八个数字的特征值和
same eight numbers the eigenvalues and
特征向量和真正的关键
the eigenvectors and really the key
点是什么是矩阵
point is what is the matrix of
特征向量所以让我们写一下
eigenvectors so let's just write that
向下，所以矩阵是特征向量
down so the matrix the eigen vector
矩阵大小为n的所有循环S--
matrix for all circulant s-- of size n
它们都具有相同的特征向量
they all have the same eigen vectors
包括p全部循环c
including including p all circulant c of
大小和包括大小为n的p
size and including p of size n which
我们就是这样的
where that's what we so what's the
特征向量矩阵是什么
eigenvector matrix what are the
特征向量和第一个向量
eigenvectors well the first vector
就像他们所有人一样
is all one's just as their so that's an
p右的特征向量因为如果我
eigenvector of p right because if I
乘以PII做一个循环移位
multiply by P I I do a shift a cyclic
转移，我已经拥有了下一个
shift and I've got all one's the next
特征向量是W的权力，让我
eigenvector is powers of W and let me
提醒你一切都会成真
remind you everything is going to be
W的功率为2pi，超过N
powers of W e to the 2 pi I over N
这是一个复杂的数字，只有一英寸
it's that complex number that's one inch
圆的方式，所以这是什么
of the way round so that's C so what
如果我乘以P它就会发生
happens if I multiply that by P it
改变它，它乘以W或1
shifts it and it multiplies by W or 1
W双传，W传递
over W double which is W transitive
这是另一个特征向量好吧
which is another eigenvector okay and
然后这个列表中的下一个将是
then the next one in this list will be
好好与W平方，所以它会
well being going with W squared so it'll
是第四个W到第六个W到了
be W fourth W to the sixth w to the
第八个哇等一下，所以我得到了这些
eighth whoa wait a minute so I get these
排队正确告诉我你和W一起去
lined up right tell me your goes with W
哎呀
squared up whoops
W平方现在它是W的第四个W.
W squared now it's W the fourth W the
6W到8W第十W第12
six W to the 8 W the tenth W the twelfth
和你到第十四和你保持
and W to the fourteenth and you keep
这样就是特征本征向量
going so that's the eigen eigen vector
特征值1这将发生我
with eigenvalue 1 this will happen i
具有特征值，它是w或
have the eigenvalue it's either w or of
共轭可能是共轭条
a conjugate might be the conjugate w bar
你会看到这个矩阵，那将是什么
and you see this matrix so what would be
这将是W，使得最后一个图标矢量
the last icon vector it would be w so
这是8乘8
this is 8 by 8
我要呼吁的是，傅立叶矩阵
I'm gonna call that the Fourier matrix
大小为8，它是特征向量
of size eight and it's the eigenvector
矩阵等傅里叶矩阵等于
matrix so Fourier matrix equals
特征向量矩阵所以我就是我的意思
eigenvector matrix so I'm just what I'm
说的是线性代数
saying is that the linear algebra for
这些循环S--是太棒了，他们
these circulant s-- is fantastic they
都具有相同的本征向量矩阵它
all have the same eigen vector matrix it
恰好是最重要的复杂因素
happens to be the most important complex
世界中的矩阵及其属性
matrix in the world and its properties
是金色的，它允许快速
are golden and it allows the fast
我们可以写的傅里叶变换
Fourier transform which we could write
在下一次和所有的矩阵语言
in matrix language next time and all the
项为W的所有条目的权力
entries are powers of W all the entries
是在单位圆上的一个
are in the on the unit circle at one of
那八点和最后一个人
those eight points and the last guy
将是W到第七个W到
would be W to the seventh w to the
第十四W¯¯二十前二十
fourteenth W the twenty first twenty
八点三十五分四十秒
eight thirty fifth forty seconds and
49所以W上的第四十九届会
forty nine so W of the forty-ninth would
它是最后一个平方的开始
be the last w tu7 squared it starts out
所有这些都是W到0倍0
with W to the 0 times 0 all these are
条目是你看到的图片W
the entry is yeah you see the picture W
如果W是，则xlix实际上是Wxlix
xlix what is actually W xlix if W is the
我们有W的第八个根
eighth root of one so we have W to the
8，它是1，因为我正在做8乘8
8th it's 1 because I'm doing 8 by 8 what
是W到49的力量它是一样的
is W to the 49th power W it's the same
好吧因为W是48是1
as W okay because W is a 48 is 1
对，我采取了这个和第六的力量
right I take the sixth power of this and
我得到W48说一个，所以那里有49个
I get the W 48 says one so W there 49 is
每一次都和W一样
the same as W every every ever every
列中矩阵的每个条目都是一个
column every entry in the matrix is a
W的力量，如果实际上是权力
power of W and if in fact that power is
只是列号乘以房间号
just column number times the room number
是啊
yeah
所以那些是好的矩阵
so those are those are the good matrices
这样就是正交矩阵
so that so that is an orthogonal matrix
哦，差不多它不是
oh well almost it's not it has
正交列，但它没有
orthogonal columns but it doesn't have
正交列什么是什么
orthonormal columns what's the what's
该列的该列的长度
the length of that column of that column
矢量平方根八右我加
vector square root of eight right I add
上升1平方八次，我拿走了
up 1 squared eight times and I take the
平方根我得到了平方根
square root I get the square root of
八，所以这真的是一个正方形
eight so so this is really it's a square
正交矩阵的八倍的根
root of eight times an orthogonal matrix
当然广场基地只是一个
of course the square base just a a
数来划分出来，使矩阵
number to divide out to make matrix to
使列正交而不是
make the columns orthonormal instead of
只是正交，但我怎么知道
just orthogonal but how do I know that
那些是正交的，我知道
those are orthogonal huh well I know
他们必须是，但我想看到它
they have to be but I'd like to see it
显然为什么那个矢量正交
clearly why is that vector orthogonal to
那个向量首先是他们必须的
that vector first of all they have to be
因为矩阵是一个普通矩阵
because the matrix is a normal matrix
正常矩阵有正交哦是的
normal matrices have orthogonal oh yeah
我怎么知道这是一个正常的矩阵哦
how do I know it's a normal matrix oh I
想我可以做测试，如果我有
guess I can do the test if I have
[掌声]
[Applause]
如果我有排列P我知道
if I have the permutation P I know that
P转置P等于PP转置
P transpose P equals P P transpose
排列通勤，所以这是正常的
permutations commute so so it's a normal
矩阵，但我想直接看到原因
matrix but I'd like to see directly why
是为什么是点的产品
is that why is the dot product of the
第一个或第零个特征向量和
first or the zeroth eigen vector and the
下一个特征向量等于零让我服用
next eigenvector equals zero let me take
点积1倍1是11倍
that dot product 1 times 1 is 1 1 times
w是w^1倍数W广场W¯¯方达
w is w 1 times W squares W squared up to
W到第七，我想我要去
W to the seventh I guess I'm going to
完成等于0那就是什么
finish that equals 0 well that's what's
说那些数字是真的
that saying those numbers are the are
这些是我的照片中的那些点
the are these points in my picture those
八点，所以八点
eight points so those are the eight
进入该列的数字
numbers that go into the that column of
那个特征向量为什么会增加
that eigen vector why do they add to
零你怎么看一些那些说
zero how do you see that some of those
八个数字是零是对称性
eight numbers is zero yeah the symmetry
当我添加那个人时会这样做-那个
would do it when I add that guy - that
W到零或W到8或W
guy W to the zero or W to the 8th or W
为零
to zero
是的，当我添加一个减去一个我得到
yeah when I add one and minus one I get
零，我有这些家伙我得零
zero and I had these guys I get zero
当我把这些添加成对但但是
when I add these these by pairs but but
怎么样三乘三所以三通过
what about a three by three so three by
三，我会去W，这将是
three I'll go to W to the this would be
e到2pi超过3然后这会
e to the 2 pi over 3 and then this would
是W到4PI这将是W平方
be W to the 4 PI this would be W squared
e将4PI超过3，我相信，
e to the 4 PI over 3 and I believe that
这三个向量添加到0的广告
those ads those three vectors add to 0
因此他们与...正交
and therefore they're orthogonal to the
一一一
one-one-one
Argan矢量因为点积
Argan vector because the dot product
只会保释只是想添加那些
will just bail just want to add those
三个数字，为什么这是真的
three numbers so why is that true
一加要么2PI超过3或者加
one plus either 2 PI over 3 plus either
4超过3的PI等于上课的最后一分钟
4 PI over 3 equals last minute of class
今天我们可以弄清楚如何做到这一点
today we can figure out how to do that
好吧，我可以得到一个公式
well I could get a formula for that that
总和是1我可以得到一个封闭的表格和
sum is 1 I could get a closed form and
检查我得到答案0快
check that I get the answer 0 the quick
可能会看到它的方式
way to see it is maybe
假设我将e乘以2pi
suppose I multiply by e to the 2 pi over
3所以我乘以每个词，让我们看看
3 so I multiply every term so let's see
2PI超过3e到4PI超过3和
the 2 PI over 3 e to the 4 PI over 3 and
e到6PI3，好吧我该怎么办？
e to the 6 PI over 3 okay what do I
从中学到它是一样的因为e
learn from this it's the same because e
到6PI超过3是1就是那个
to the 6 PI over 3 is is 1 that's that's
2pi我是1，所以我也一样
2 pi I so that's 1 so I got the same
有人加上这个加上这个加号
someone Plus this Plus this this Plus
这加一，所以我得到了相同的金额
this plus one so I got the same sum when
我乘以那个数和那个总和
I multiplied by that number and that sum
必须是0我不能得到相同的总和我
has to be 0 I can't get the same sum I
不能乘以此并获得相同
can't multiply by this and get the same
回答，除非我乘以0这样
answer unless I'm multiplying 0 so that
告诉我，那也是奇怪的
shows me that that that also in the odd
当n是奇数我也有那些n
when n is odd I also have that those n
数字加到0确定那些是
numbers adding to 0 ok that's those are
基本的美丽画面
the basic the beautiful picture of the
特征值是特征向量
eigen values the eigen vectors being
正交然后是实际的细节
orthogonal and then the actual details
这些特征向量是好的
here of what those eigen vectors are ok
好，我希望你有一个好的周末，
good I hope you have a good weekend and
所以我们只有一个半星期
so we've just got a week and a half
第一类的左边可能有一个
left of class I may probably have one
关于傅立叶，然后再做更多的事情
more thing to do about Fourier and then
我们会回到其他主题但是问一下
we'll come back to other topics but ask
任何问题和你的话题
any questions and that you'd topics that
你想看到这里包括哪里
you'd like to see included here where
we're closing out 1806 five while you
我们现在要关门了18065，而你
伙计们做项目好吗谢谢
guys do the projects okay thank you